http://www.airaidsales.com/privacy

We use cookies to personalize content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyze our traffic.
We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners.
Learn more.
Allow Cookies
Dismiss
Home
Privacy Policy
FIND YOUR PART | SEARCH BY:
All
Enter your Vehicle Identification Number (VIN)
Last Modified: 9/18/20
Thank you for visiting this website. K&N Engineering, Inc., by and
through our subsidiary, K&N Filters (Europe) Ltd. (“K&N,” “we”,
“us”, or “our”) is responsible for this website and is the controller of
data provided to us through it. We respect your privacy and aim to protect
it along with your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you how
we collect, process, and control your personal data when you visit us at
this website, or at any of our other related sites, listed here, which are collectively referred to as the K&N Sites. It also applies to
situations when we send you communications that you request from us.
Advertisements displayed to you when you use our Sites and elsewhere may be
customized and targeted to your interests and known preferences based on
your personal data collection through our services. Please read below for
more information about advertising and your rights.
1.
Who We Are
K&N has its principal place of business at P.O. Box 1329 Riverside, CA
92502. Any questions about your data privacy or this privacy policy, please
contact us at
privacy@knfilters.com, or at
physical address.
Third Party Links
This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and
applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may
allow third parties to collect or share data about you. When you visit a
page that includes one of these sharing tools, the third party company that
operates the tool may be collecting information about your browser, device,
and online activity through its own tracking technologies and subject to
its own separate privacy policy. We do not control these third-party
websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you
leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every
website you visit.
2.
The Data We Collect About You When You Visit K&N Sites
We collect several different types of personal data, which is information
relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, from you
depending on how you interact with our K&N Sites. Most often, the
information we collect is related to the purchase of a product from our
website. This information includes your full name, email address, shipping
address, billing address, and phone number (“Contact Information”). When
you make a purchase from our site, we collect credit card payment or
financial account information in order to process the sale (“Billing
Information”). If you sign up to receive emails, newsletters, or other
information from us, we collect your name and email address (“Marketing
Information”).
Some of the personal data we request from you is required in order for you
to use our Sites, including ordering products and/or services through them.
If you do not wish to provide such personal data to us, you are not
obligated to, but you may not be able to use a particular features of our
Sites, including ordering products, as a result. Below are some examples of
where and how we collect personal data from you.
Product Purchases
: When you purchase products offered through one of our Sites, we
collect your credit card and other payment information and keep a history
of your purchases. We use this information for purposes such as to process
your orders, to better assist you when you visit or contact us in the
future, as well as to improve our product offerings when we send you
information about these in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Selecting Products
: When you use our “Search By Vehicle” “Search By Keyword” and “Search By
Part” features, we may collect the information provided through those
features and associate it with other personal information. We use this
information for purposes such as to process your orders, to better assist
you when you visit or contact us in the future, as well as to improve our
product offerings when we send you information about these in accordance
with this Privacy Policy.
Providing Product Reviews
: If you review one of our products or provide feedback and testimonials,
we may post this data on our website and in other marketing advertising. We
do so to provide customers with third-party feedback and reviews from
actual customers, which we believe helps provide a more honest buying
experience. We also use it to evaluate our own products and make
improvements to our products and/or services.
Customer Service Communications
: We offer a live chat feature to help provide you with the best customer
service we can offer. If you choose to use this feature, we may collect
specific information about you necessary to communicate with you and
respond to your customer services requests. When you call one of our
customer service representatives, or e-mail us with a comment or question,
you may be asked for information that identifies you, such as your name,
mailing address, order number, postal code and/or telephone number, to help
us promptly answer your question. We retain this information as necessary
to assist you in the future, for instance with any further queries you may
have. We also use your feedback, suggestions and comments to monitor and/or
improve our publications, product offerings, and Services, among other
things.
Promotions or Surveys
: When you enter a contest or sweepstakes ("promotion") or participate in a
survey or poll ("survey") we may ask you to provide your name, address,
phone number and e-mail address. Sometimes we use third-party services to
administer and administer and conduct our promotions, so if you use those
services when participating in a promotions the policies, including privacy
policies, of those third-parties will apply in addition to ours. We use the
information we collect on promotion entry forms to administer your
participation in the promotions and for other purposes stated on the entry
form. Our surveys ask for opinions on various issues and may be sponsored
by our advertisers and partners. Information obtained through surveys is
aggregated and used internally. We also share survey information with
advertisers and marketing partners in an aggregated form that does not
personally identify you. In the event personal information is requested as
part of a survey, such personal information will only be provided to
unaffiliated third parties after ensuring that depending on the
circumstances you have either consented or not objected.
Website Information
: We collect the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our
Sites and clickstream and other related information, such as information
about your computer or device, web browser and operating system and their
settings, the referring page that linked you to our site, the pages,
content or ads you see or click on during your visit and when and for how
long you do so, items you download, the next website you visit when you
leave our site, and any search terms you have entered on our site
(“Technical Data”). We use this information to monitor and improve our
website, products, and services.
When we collect data that does not identify you as a natural person, we are
permitted to use and disclose this information for any purpose,
notwithstanding anything contrary in this Privacy Policy, except where
prohibited by law.
3. Cookies and Web Beacons
Like many websites, our server logs capture Technical Data automatically as
your browse the particular K&N Sites. We do this through several means.
Cookies
: To enhance your experience on our Sites, we place "cookies" on your
computer or device. Cookies are small text files that we place in your
computer or device to store your preferences. Other information you provide
to us may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. A cookie assigns a
unique numerical identifier to your Web browser or device, and may enable
us to recognize you as the same user who has used our Sites, and relate
your use of the Sites to other information about you. To learn more about
how we use cookies on Sites based in the EU, please visit the Cookie Policy
on the Site you are using.
Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser option
so that you will not receive cookies and you can also delete existing
cookies from your browser. However, you may find that some parts of the
site will not function properly if you have refused cookies or similar
tracking technologies and you should be aware that disabling cookies or
similar tracking technologies might prevent you from accessing some of our
content. However, your viewing of editorial content may be hampered. If you
wish to block cookies, go to
http://www.allaboutcookies.org
/ to find out how, or check your browser’s instructions.
Local Shared Objects
: Local shared objects, such as Flash cookies, also may be stored on your
computer or device. Local shared objects operate a lot like cookies, but
cannot be managed in the same way. Depending on how local shared objects
are enabled on your computer or device, you may be able to manage them
using software settings. For information on managing Flash cookies, for
example, see
http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html
.
HTML 5
: HTML5, the language some websites are coded in, may be used to store
information on your computer or device about your Site usage activities.
This information may be retrieved by us to help us manage our Sites, such
as by giving us information about how our Sites are being used by our
visitors, how they can be improved, and to customize them for our users.
Cache Cookies
: Cache cookies, such as eTags, may be used to identify your computer or
device as the same computer or device that visited a Site or Sites in the
past.
Web Beacons
: Our websites may also use small pieces of code called "web beacons" or
"clear gifs" to collect advertising metrics, such as counting page views,
promotion views, or advertising responses. A web beacon is an electronic
image called a single-pixel or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain
types of information, such as a user's cookie number, time and date of a
page view, and description of the page where the web beacon is placed.
These web beacons may be used to deliver cookies that conform to our cookie
policy above.
Mobile Device IDs and Location-Based Information
: Certain mobile devices, including smart phones and tablet devices,
contain unique device IDs that can be used to identify their physical
location. Some mobile device IDs are persistent, while others may be
resettable by accessing the device’s privacy settings. Mobile devices also
typically transmit caller ID data (which may include a phone number) when
used to transmit a telephone call or text message. When you use mobile
devices to access our Services, we may collect and transmit unique device
IDs and collect caller ID data, as well as other information about your
device, including without limitation, your wireless carrier, the make,
model, operating system, capacity and settings of your device, the names,
package IDs and versions of other software you have downloaded to your
device and information about how you interact with and navigate within our
Service. With your consent, we or our authorized service providers and
partners also may use precise geolocation technology such as GPS or Wi-Fi
triangulation or mobile Bluetooth beacon technology to collect information
about the exact location of your mobile device. Precise location
information may be collected both while you are using one of our mobile
applications and continuously over time while our apps are not in use but
are running in the background of your device. You can withdraw your consent
to the further collection and use of your precise device location data
through any of our mobile apps by accessing your device’s privacy settings
as further explained below.
We use cookies (and other analytics/tracking tools) to understand usage of
the Sites and to improve our content and offerings and to deliver
advertisements that you might be interested in. For example, we use cookies
to personalize your experience on our Sites (e.g., to recognize you by name
when you return to our site, to save your password in password-protected
areas, to enable shopping carts, or to tailor content or product and
service offerings). These tracking technologies may be deployed by us
and/or by our service providers or partners on our behalf.
4.
How We Use Your Personal Data.
We will only use your personal data when allowed by law. Generally, we will
use your personal data: (a) where we need to perform the contract we are
about to enter into or have entered into with you; (b) where it is
necessary for our legitimate interests and your interests and fundamental
rights do not override those interests; and (c) where we need to comply
with a legal or regulatory obligation. Generally, uses include the
following actions:
Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your
personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct
marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the
right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.
Purposes for which we will use your personal data
Below is a chart of some of the common ways in which we process your
personal data. We have identified what our legitimate interests are where
appropriate. Note that we may process your personal data for more than one
lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your
data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground
we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground
has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/Activity
Type of data
Lawful basis for processing including basis of
legitimate interest
To fulfill a purchase order.
Contact Information
Billing Information
In furtherance of performance of a contract with you.
Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy notice.
Contact Information
Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To administer and protect our business and this website
(including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system
maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data).
Contact Information
Technical Data
Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our
business, provision of administration and IT services,
network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a
business reorganization or group restructuring exercise)
To provide you with information and marketing
communications about our products and services.
Contact Information
Consent
Legitimate Interests
To respond to customer service requests including order
status and chat communications.
Contact Information
Legitimate Interest
Consent
5.
Disclosures Of Your Personal Data
From time to time, we may need to share your personal data with others.
Third Party Service Providers
. We may share your information, including Contact Data and Technical Data,
with third party service providers who perform various functions to enable
us to provide our devices and help us operate our business, such as website
design, sending email communications, fraud detection and prevention,
customer care, or performing analytics. Our contracts with these third
parties require them to maintain the confidentiality of the personal data
we provide to them, only act on our behalf and under our instructions, and
not use personal data for purposes other than the product or service
they're providing to us or on our behalf.
Protection of K&N and Others
. We may share personal data when we believe it is appropriate to enforce
or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or protect the rights,
property, or safety of K&N, our products and services, our users, or
others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and
organizations for fraud protection and risk reduction. This does not
include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personal data of
our customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set
forth in this Notice.
Response to Subpoenas and Other Legal Requests
. We may share your information with courts, law enforcement agencies, or
other government bodies when we have a good faith belief we're required or
permitted to do so by law, including to meet national security or law
enforcement requirements, to protect our company, or to respond to a court
order, subpoena, search warrant, or other law enforcement request.
Sale of Our Business
. If we sell, merge, or transfer any part of our business, we may be
required to share your information. If so, you will be asked if you'd like
to stop receiving promotional information following any change of control.
With your Consent
. Other than as set out above, we will provide you with notice and the
opportunity to choose when your personal data may be shared with other
third parties.
6. Your Choices Regarding Personal Data
You have choices regarding how we use your personal data. We respect your
choices and attempt to honor them whenever possible.
Email Marketing
You can remove yourself from promotional emails by clicking the unsubscribe
button that appears in the email you receive or by emailing your
unsubscribe request to us at privacy@knfilters.com. Please note that it
sometimes takes a few days to process unsubscribe requests, but we take
efforts to respond to these requests as reasonably practicable. Also, if
you receive third-party email offers, you may unsubscribe from those emails
by clicking on the unsubscribe button contained within those emails.
Analytics and Interest Based Advertising
Please see our Cookie Policy regarding how we use tracking technologies and
your choices regarding them.
Precise Device Location Tracking
Precise location tracking can be turned off and on using your mobile
devices location privacy settings. All major operating systems provide
their own instructions for how to turn off precise location sharing and
these instructions are usually found in the device’s privacy settings.
7. Data Security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal
data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way,
altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to
those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a
business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our
instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We have put
in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and
will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are
legally required to do so.
8. EU Data Subjects Terms
Privacy Rights
EU data subjects have certain rights with respect to your personal data
that we collect and process. We respond to all requests we receive from
individuals in the EEA wishing to exercise their data protection rights in
accordance with applicable data protection laws.
Access, Correction or Deletion
. You may request access to, correction of, or deletion of your
personal data. You can often go directly into the Service under Account
Settings to take these actions.
Please note that even if you request for your personal data to be deleted,
certain aspects may be retained for us to: meet our legal or regulatory
compliance (e.g. maintaining records of transactions you have made with
us); exercise, establish or defend legal claims; and to protect against
fraudulent or abusive activity on our Service. Data retained for these
purposes will be handled as described in “Data Retention” subsection,
below.
Objection
. You may object to processing of your personal data where we are
relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there
is something about your particular situation which makes you want to
object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your
fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object
where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing
purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling
legitimate grounds to process your information which override your
rights and freedoms.
Restriction
. You have the right to ask us to suspend the processing of your
personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to
establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is
unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to
hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to
establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to
our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding
legitimate grounds to use it.
Portability
. You have the right to request the transfer of your personal data to
you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you
have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used,
machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated
information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where
we used the information to perform a contract with you.
Withdraw Consent
. If we have collected and processed your personal data with your
consent, you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your
consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted
prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your
personal data conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other
than consent.
File a complaint
. You have the right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority
about our collection and processing of your personal data.
To file a request or take action on one of your rights, please contact us
at the contact details provided. You will not have to pay a fee to access
your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we
may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded,
repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your
request in these circumstances.
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm
your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to
exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure
that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to
receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in
relation to your request to speed up our response. We try to respond to all
legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer
than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a
number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
Data Retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil
the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying
any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the
appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount,
nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm
from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for
which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those
purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. In
some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data (see “EU Data
Subjects Legal Rights”). In some circumstances we may anonymize your
personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for
research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information
indefinitely without further notice to you.
International Data Transfers
The personal data you provide to us is being transmitted to us and
processed in the United States and by our affiliates and their service
providers in jurisdictions where we or they operate. Your personal data
will be protected subject to this privacy policy and contracts that impose
data protections as required by the country where your data was collected.
By using our Services you consent to the transfer, processing, storage and
access of your personal data of your personal data in and/or outside of the
jurisdiction in which you reside. Courts and other authorities in these
jurisdictions may, in certain circumstances, be entitled to access your
personal data. If your personal data is collected in Europe, we will
transfer your personal data subject to suitable safeguards, including
standard contractual clauses where appropriate.
9. Children’s Privacy
We are committed to complying with the Children's Online Privacy Protection
Act (COPPA). K&N Sites and services are not directed to children under
the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from
children under the age of 16. If we receive personal information that we
discover was provided by a child under the age of 16, we will promptly
destroy such information. Additional information is available on the Direct
Marketing Association's home page at http://www.the-dma.org. If you would
like to learn more about COPPA, visit the Federal Trade Commission home
page at http://www.ftc.gov.
10. California Privacy Rights
If you are a California resident, you also have the ability to ask us for a
notice identifying the categories of personal information, as defined by
California Civil Code Section 1798.83, we share with our affiliates and/or
third parties for their direct marketing purposes and the contact
information for such affiliates and/or third parties (under California
Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84). If you are a California resident and
would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to
privacy@knfilters.com
11. Updates to Our Privacy Policy
We may revise this Privacy Policy, so please review it periodically. If you
continue to visit this Site and use the Services made available to you
after such changes have been made, you hereby provide your consent to the
changes.
We will post any updates to this Privacy Policy on this webpage, and the
revised version will be effective when it is posted. If you are concerned
about how your information is used, please bookmark this page and read this
Privacy Policy periodically.
12. Yeti Giveaway & Contests
• Eligibility: The Contest is open only to legal residents of the United States who are at least
eighteen (18) years old. Employees of Airaid (“Sponsor”), as well as the immediate family
(spouse, parents, siblings, and children) and household members of those employees, are not
eligible to enter.
• How to Enter
User must:
• Tag three of your friends who need to know about this giveaway!
Winner Selection and Notification. The potential winner will be selected in a random drawing
from among all eligible entries received. Drawing will be held on September 21st, 2020.
Sponsor’s decisions as to the administration and operation of the Giveaway and the selection of the potential winner are final and binding in all matters related to the Giveaway.
Additional Details:
Shares are appreciated, but not necessary.
Contest runs 9/21/20 to 9/23/2020
Winners will be announced on 9/24/20.
Disclosures:
***This contest is only available to those living inside the United States***
***This promotion is in no way sponsored, endorsed, or administered by, or
associated with Instagram. As such, Instagram is released of any and all liability
from each entrant and participant.***
• Message and data rates may apply to entries posted from a mobile device.
• By entering, you indicate your full agreement to these Official Rules and Sponsor’s decisions
regarding the Giveaway, which are final and binding. Winning a prize is contingent upon
fulfilling all requirements in these Official Rules.
• Potential Winner Requirements: Except where prohibited, a potential winner will be required
to complete and return an affidavit of eligibility and a liability/publicity release. If a potential
winner fails to sign and return these documents within three (3) business days, Sponsor may
select an alternate potential winner in his/her place according to the Judging Criteria.
• Prizes: One (1) Yeti Tumbler. Not redeemable for cash, credit or gift card and no exchange,
transfer or substitution permitted unless K&N, in its sole discretion, determines otherwise.
• General Conditions: In the event that the operation, security, or administration of the
Contest is impaired in any way, Sponsor may, in its sole discretion, either: (a) suspend the
Contest to address the impairment and then resume the Contest in a manner that best
conforms to the spirit of these Official Rules; or (b) award the prizes based on the Judging
Criteria from among the eligible entries received up to the time of the impairment. Sponsor
reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to disqualify any individual who tampers with the
operation of the Contest, violates these Official Rules, or acts in an unsportsmanlike or
disruptive manner. Sponsor reserves the right to seek damages from any person who seeks to
undermine the legitimate operation of the Contest. Failure by Sponsor to enforce any term of
these Official Rules shall not constitute a waiver of that provision. Proof of sending any
communication to Sponsor by mail shall not be deemed proof of receipt of that communication
by Sponsor. The Contest is subject to federal, state, and local laws and regulations and is void
where prohibited.
• Release and Limitations of Liability: By entering, you agree to release and hold harmless
Sponsor, Instagram, their respective parents, subsidiaries, affiliates, and each of their
respective officers, directors, employees, and agents (the “Released Parties”) from and against
any claim or cause of action arising out of participation in the Contest or receipt or use of any
prize, including, but not limited to: (a) unauthorized human intervention in the Contest; (b)
technical errors related to computers, servers, providers, or telephone or network lines; (c)
printing errors; (d) lost, late, postage-due, misdirected, or undeliverable mail; (e) errors in the
administration of the Contest or the processing of entries; or (g) injury or damage to persons or
property. You further agree that in any cause of action, in no event shall the Released Parties be
liable for attorney’s fees. You waive the right to claim any damages whatsoever, including, but
not limited to, punitive, consequential, direct, or indirect damages.
• Privacy and Publicity: Any information you submit as part of the Contest will be treated in
accordance with Sponsor’s Privacy Policy. See https://www.airaid.com/privacy for Airaid privacy
Policy. Except where prohibited participation in the Contest constitutes an entrant’s consent to
Sponsor’s use of his/her name, likeness, voice, opinions, biographical information, and state of
residence for promotional purposes in any media without further payment or consideration.
• Disputes: You agree that any and all disputes, claims, and causes of action arising out of, or
connected with, the Contest or any prize awarded shall be resolved individually, without resort
to any form of class action, and exclusively by the appropriate court located in Riverside
County, California. All issues and questions concerning the construction, validity, interpretation
and enforceability of these Official Rules, your rights and obligations, or the rights and
obligations of the Sponsor in connection with the Contest, shall be governed by, and construed
in accordance with, the laws of the State of California, without giving effect to any choice of law
or conflict of law rules (whether of California or any other jurisdiction), which would cause the
application of the laws of any jurisdiction other than California.
• Winner Information: Winners will be posted on Sponsor’s Instagram page after the Contest
ends.
• Sponsor and Administrator: The Contest is sponsored by Airaid. The Contest is not
sponsored, endorsed or administered by, or associated with, Instagram.
13. How to Contact Us
If you have any questions or wish to register a complaint in relation to
this Privacy Notice or the manner in which your personal data is used by
us, please contact us by any of the following means:
By Email: privacy@knfilters.com
By Post: P.O. Box 1329 Riverside, CA 92502
Warning!
We have detected that you are using an outdated browser that will not allow you to access certain features of our website.
We strongly recommend installing an updated browser, such as Google Chrome, for an improved browsing experience.
Chat Now
Copyright © 2020 AIRAID. All Rights Reserved.
California Transparency in Supply Chains Act
Privacy Policy
Terms of Use
